Register of the Poland. Delegacja przy Lidze Narodów Telegrams
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Delegacja przy Lidze Narodów telegrams,
1933-1939
59037
Poland. Delegacja przy Lidze Narodów
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Telegrams and logbook transcripts of telegrams sent and received, relating to Polish foreign relations during the interwar period and Polish participation in the League of Nations. A digital copy of this entire collection is available at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/38/0/-/.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (1 reel).
Digital copy in Poland's National Digital Archive at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/38/0/-/. It was digitized from microfilm by the Polish State Archives.
Historical Note
Polish delegation to the League of Nations.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains a small but very significant portion of the correspondence sent and received by the Polish delegation to the League of Nations, mainly in the second half of the 1930s. The telegrams and letters relate to Poland's foreign relations during the interwar period and to its participation in the League of Nations, and serve as a good source for the study of the international tensions that led to the outbreak of World War II.
These documents were formerly part of the Polish Foreign Ministry collection, acquired by the Hoover Archives in 1959, and were accessioned in the early 1990s as a separate collection.
A microfilm copy of these materials has been deposited in the State Archives of Poland in Warsaw.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
League of Nations--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations.
Series Description
- Coded Telegrams and Letters, 1933-1939. (Box 1-2)
  Logbooks of incoming and outgoing telegrams and letters, arranged chronologically
Container List
- CODED TELEGRAMS AND LETTERS, 1933-1939. (Box 1)
  Logbooks
  - Letters
    - 1934-1935 - Incoming (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1935 - Outgoing (Folder 1: 2)
  - Telegrams, 1935
    - Incoming (Folder 1: 3)
    - Outgoing (Folder 1: 4)
  - Telegrams and letters
    - 1933 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1934
      - Incoming (Folder 1: 6)
      - Outgoing (Folder 1: 7)
    - 1936 (Box 2)
      - Incoming (Folder 2: 1)
      - Outgoing (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1937
      - Incoming (Folder 2: 3)
      - Outgoing (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1938 - 1939 September
      - Incoming (Folder 2: 5)
      - Outgoing (Folder 2: 6)